Guide to the Rice University Beer-Bike Records, 1957-2023 UA 095
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Beer-Bike Records
1957-2023
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 095
8.75 Linear Feet (12 boxes)
The collection represents the history of Beer-Bike, the race rules, resolution, reports, newsclippings, realia, and financial lists as well as some programs.
Organizational Sketch
When the Beer-Bike race first began in 1957, it was a competition between two residential colleges, run on the campus inner loop, with the victorious college receiving a keg of beer from the loser. At that time, the people who rode the bikes were the same as those who chugged the beer. The Beer-Bike race of today is more of an intercollege bike race where 10 non-riding people chug between riders.
In the early days, riders and drinkers worked out for only a couple of days before the race, just to make the team and get in the spirit of things. The beer drinkers opened the taps of their cans with a standard opener and the riders rode "English Bikes." The crowd, which numbered only a few friends, stood anywhere they pleased to view the action. In those days, the race was a test of mechanical durability as well as speed, for the same bike was used for the whole race. This involved ripping the incoming rider off his speeding machine, slapping on a fresh rider, and casting him out in front of the pit. The spent rider was then scooped up and removed from the course. During this time, the beer drinkers knocked off their refreshments in the living-room time of six or seven seconds. High speed was not necessary because of the time involved in changing riders.
In, 1968, Beer-Bike moved to the Rice Stadium. The first women's race took place in 1972 when Brown and Jones Colleges competed. In 1976, the seed of the parade tradition was planted when Sid Richardson College entered with torches, followed by a brass band playing the theme for the Olympic Games. Alumni participated in the first alumni race in 1982. In 1987, when the drinking age changed from 18 to 21, water was offered at Beer-Bike for the first time to quench underage students' thirst.
Today, technology dominates the race. Nearly all the bikes are of the ten-speed type ridden in the Tour de France (some machines costing as much as $600). The beer drinkers have special 14 oz. "tall boy" cans with mouthpieces custom fitted and thoroughly tested. Several bikers are used throughout the race with the gears matched to the rider's style of riding. The speed of the beer team now counts heavily since the outgoing rider is mounted and ready to go before the incoming rider reaches the pit.
College and bike teams practice for months ahead of the race, and making the team of 10, or at least securing a spot as an alternate, is a sought-after goal for many college members. Parade coordinators plan weeks in advance to devise an innovative parade float, or theme song, or chant, or mode of transportation to the track on race day. Team participants seek financial sponsors, design team and college t-shirts, work to determine the optimal chug technique, and hold coordination practices to ensure that a biker starts riding precisely as the chugger finishes. Every year race coordinators hold meetings to choose team colors, to schedule practice races, and to revise or change rules.
Excerpted from "Sallyport," April-May 1992, "Thresher," April 7, 2000, and "The Beer Bike Race," by Jim Llamas, Captain.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of the history of Beer-Bike, the race rules, resolution, reports, realia, and financial lists as well as some programs. The largest part of the collection is made up of articles published in various campus publications such as the "Thresher," "Rice News," the "Sallyport," and other news sources.
Acquisition Information
Some of the records had been part of the Woodson Research Center Information Files. A large portion of the files were given to Woodson in August 2001 by Jen Cooper (Will Rice, BA, 1990) who was the the Student Media Advisor, Office of Student Media and a former Beer-Bike participant. In 2014, Julie Neisler, Assistant Director of Student Activities, donated materials.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Related Archival Materials
The items contained in this collection are related to Rice Program Council's Beer Bike and its corresponding events. For information on the colleges' role in the event, please see the college records.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Social life and customs
Document Types
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Programs (Publications); Records (documents); Registers (Lists)
Subjects (Corporations)
Beer Bike cycling event; Rice University
- Series I: General, 1957-2019, 99952
  - Course, 2001; 99965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History, 99964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - News Clippings, 1950s; 99963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - News Clippings, 1960s; 99962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - News Clippings, 1970s; 99961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - News Clippings, 1980s; 99960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - News Clippings, 1990s; 99959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - News Clippings, 2000s; 99958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - News Clippings, 2010s; 99957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series II: Media, 1979-2006, 176209
  - Beer Bike (reel to reel), 1979; 176210 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Beer-Bike Race - JLC (VHS and DVD) and Beer-Bike Trilogy, 1988, 1986-1987-1988; 176211 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Team Wiess - Beer Bike by Christian Nixon (VHS), 1993; 176212 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Beer-Bike (DVD), 2005; 176213 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Beer-Bike (DVD), 2006; 176214 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series III: Beer-Bike Memorabilia, 1980-2019, 99945
  - Belt buckle, 2010; 176215 (Box 2, Item -)
  - Glass tumbler, 1999; 176217 (Box 2, Item -)
  - Weizen glass, 2000; 176218 (Box 2, Item -)
  - Weizen glass, 2000; 176219 (Box 3, Item -)
  - Glass beer mug (2), 2001; 176220 (Box 3, Item -)
  - Glass tumbler, 2002; 176221 (Box 4, Item -)
  - Plastic water bottle, 2010; 176222 (Box 4, Item -)
  - Weizen glass, 2011; 176223 (Box 4, Item -)
  - Beer stein, 2013; 176224 (Box 5, Item -)
  - Rondelet Beer Bike Race Trophy, 1957-1968; 176225 (Box 5, Item -)
  - Beer Bike T-Shirt "Will Rice: Nonpareil", 1980 (Box 5, Item -)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Materials donated by Walter Underwood in 2019.
  - Beer Bike T-Shirt "Will Rice College: Perfecto", 1980 (Box 5, Item -)
  - Beer Bike T-Shirt "Will Rice College", 1987 (Box 5, Item -)
    Scope and Contents
    Donated by Tom Perrault.
  - Beer Bike Judge T-Shirt, 2000; 176226 (Box 5, Item -)
  - Beer Bike Judge T-Shirt, 2002; 176227 (Box 5, Item -)
  - Beer Bike Judge T-Shirt, 2006; 176228 (Box 5, Item -)
  - Blue Beer Bike T-Shirt, 2010; 176229 (Box 5, Item -)
  - Black Beer Bike T-Shirt (2), 2010; 176230 (Box 5, Item -)
  - Beer Bike Caregiver T-Shirt, 2010; 176231 (Box 6, Item -)
  - Beer Bike Judge T-Shirt, 2010; 176232 (Box 6, Item -)
  - Beer Bike Security T-Shirt, 2010; 176233 (Box 6, Item -)
  - Black Beer Bike T-Shirt, 2011; 176234 (Box 6, Item -)
  - Beer Bike Security T-Shirt, 2012; 176235 (Box 6, Item -)
  - Beer Bike Judge T-Shirt, 2014; 184857 (Box 6, Item -)
  - Beer Bike Security T-Shirt, 2014; 184858 (Box 6, Item -)
  - One Eyed Willy Week T-Shirt, n.d.; 176236 (Box 6, Item -)
  - Willy Gone Wild Week T-Shirt, n.d.; 176237 (Box 6, Item -)
  - Willy Wonka and the Chocolate Brewery T-Shirt, 176238 (Box 6, Item -)
  - Plastic cup, March 21, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Beer Bike Wristband, 2019 (Box 6)
  - Beer Bike Drawstring Bag, 2019 (Box 6)
- Series IV: Event Planning, 1959-2019, 176239
  - General, n.d.; 176515 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Subseries A: 1959-1979, 176240
    - Correspondence, 1959, 1954, 1966, 1967; 176241 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Rules, 1961; 176246 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Judges, 1972; 176247 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Rules, 1972; 176248 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Songfest, 1972; 176249 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Rules, 1976; 176250 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Rules, 1979; 176251 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: 1982-1989, 176242
    - Correspondence, 1982; 176252 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Program, 1982; 176253 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Results and Program, 1983; 176254 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Results, 1984; 176255 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Captains, 1985; 176256 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Results, 1985; 176257 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Captains, 1986; 176258 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Results, 1986; 176259 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1987; 176260 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Judges, 1987; 176261 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Program, 1987; 176262 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Results, 1987; 176263 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Rules, 1987; 176264 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Schedule, 1987; 176265 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Results, 1988; 176266 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1989; 176267 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Program, 1989; 176268 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Results, 1989; 176269 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Rules, 1989; 176270 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Teams, 1989; 176271 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Track, 1989; 176272 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Subseries C: 1990-1999, 176243
    - Contacts, 1990; 176273 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1990; 176274 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Judges, 1990; 176275 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Meetings, 1990; 176276 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Program, 1990; 176277 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Results, 1990; 176278 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Rules, 1990; 176279 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Schedule, 1990; 176280 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Teams, 1990; 176281 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Track, 1990; 176282 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 1991; 176283 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Meetings, 1991; 176284 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Program, 1991; 176285 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Reports, 1991; 176286 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Rules, 1991; 176287 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Schedule, 1991; 176288 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Track, 1991; 176289 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Contacts, 1992; 176290 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence, 1992; 176291 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Meetings, 1992; 176292 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Program, 1992; 176293 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Results, 1992; 176294 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Rules, 1992; 176295 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Schedule, 1992; 176296 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Suggestions, 1992; 176297 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Budget, 1993; 176298 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Contacts, 1993; 176299 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence, 1993; 176300 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Meetings, 1993; 176301 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Program, 1993; 176302 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Reports, 1993; 176303 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Results, 1993; 176304 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Teams, 1993; 176305 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Budget, 1994; 176306 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Correspondence, 1994; 176307 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Judges, 1994; 176308 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Program, 1994; 176309 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Schedule, 1994; 176310 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Reports, 1994; 176311 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Rules, 1994; 176312 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Budget, 1995; 176313 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Contacts, 1995; 176314 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Correspondence, 1995; 176315 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Judges, 1995; 176316 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Meetings, 1995; 176317 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Parade, 1995; 176318 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Program, 1995; 176319 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Reports, 1995; 176320 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Results, 1995; 176321 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Rules, 1995; 176322 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Schedule, 1995; 176323 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Security, 1995; 176324 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - Teams, 1995; 176325 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Track, 1995; 176326 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Contacts, 1996; 176329 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Judges, 1996; 176330 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Meetings, 1996; 176331 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Parade, 1996; 176332 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Programs, 1996; 176333 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Rules, 1996; 176338 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Track, 1996; 176340 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Willy Week, 1996; 176341 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1997; 176353 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Judges, 1997; 176354 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Program, 1997; 176355 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Reports, 1997; 176356 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Results, 1997; 176357 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Rules, 1997; 176358 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Sponsorship, 1997; 176359 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Track, 1997; 176360 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Contacts, 1998; 176367 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1998; 176368 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Judges, 1998; 176369 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Meetings, 1998; 176370 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Parade, 1998; 176371 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Results, 1998; 176372 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Rules, 1998; 176373 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Schedule, 1998; 176374 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Sponsorship, 1998; 176375 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Track, 1998; 176376 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Contacts, 1999; 176377 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1999; 176378 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Judges, 1999; 176379 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Minutes, 1999; 176380 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Parade, 1999; 176381 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Reports, 1999; 176382 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Results, 1999; 176383 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Rules, 1999; 176384 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Track, 1999; 176385 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Subseries D: 2000-2009, 176244
    - Area Coordinator, 2000; 176386 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Budget, 2000; 176387 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Contacts, 2000; 176388 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Meetings, 2000; 176389 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Parade, 2000; 176390 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Reports, 2000; 176391 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Rules, 2000; 176392 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Schedule, 2000; 176393 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Solicitation, 2000; 183648 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Sponsors, 2000; 176394 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Track, 2000; 176395 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Area Coordinator, 2001; 176396 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - "Beer Bike Folder of Happiness", 2001; 176397 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Budget, 2001; 176398 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 2001; 176399 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Gift donations, 2001; 183649 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Judges, 2001; 176400 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Meetings, 2001; 176401 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Parade, 2001; 183650 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Participation agreement, 2001; 183652 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Program/Signs, 2001; 176402 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Reports, 2001; 176403 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Results, 2001; 176404 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Rules, 2001; 183653 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Solicitation, 2001; 183655 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Sponsors, 2001; 176405 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Track, 2001; 176406 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Violations/fines, 2001; 183656 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Willy Week, 2001; 183657 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Area Coordinator, 2002; 176407 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Bleachers, 2002; 183658 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Budget, 2002; 176408 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Communications packets, 2002; 183659 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Concessions, 2002; 183660 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Contacts, 2002; 176409 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 2002; 176410 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - "Everything You Love About Beer Bike", 2002; 176411 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Meetings, 2002; 176412 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Parade, 2002; 176413 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Reports, 2002; 176414 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Rules, 2002; 183662 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Security, 2002; 183663 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Solicitation, 2002; 183664 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Sponsorship, 2002; 176415 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Track, 2002; 176416 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Unjackables, 2002; 176417 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Violations, 2002; 183665 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Willy Week, 2002; 183666 (Box 9, Box 36)
    - Area Coordinators, 2003; 176418 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Budget, 2003; 176419 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - College Coordinators, 2003; 176420 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Contacts, 2003; 176421 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, 2003; 176422 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Meetings, 2003; 176423 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Parade, 2003; 176424 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Participation agreement, 2003; 183667 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Publicity, 2003; 176425 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Reports, 2003; 176426 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Results, 2003; 176427 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Rules, 2003; 176428 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Schedule, 2003; 176429 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Security, 2003; 176430 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Sponsors, 2003; 176431 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Track, 2003; 176432 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Violations, 2003; 183668 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Williams, Holly - Coordinator Journal, 2003; 176433 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Area Coordinators, 2004; 176434 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Budget, 2004; 176435 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Campus-Wide Coordinator, 2004; 176436 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - College Coordinators, 2004; 176437 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Concessions, 2004; 176438 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Contacts, 2004; 176439 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 2004; 176440 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Judges, 2004; 176441 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Media (CD), 2004; 176442 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      General Note
      This CD contains files on fines and T-Shirt designs. There are quite a few files that cannot be opened, and it is unclear what program was used to create them. Excluding repeats, any files that could be opened were printed and placed within a corresponding subject folder.
    - Meetings, 2004; 176443 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Parade, 2004; 176444 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Participation agreement, 2004; 183670 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Program, 2004; 176445 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Publicity Coordinator, 2004; 176446 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Rules, 2004; 176447 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Security, 2004; 176448 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Sponsors, 2004; 176449 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Teams, 2004; 176450 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Track, 2004; 176451 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - T-Shirts, 2004; 176452 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Unjackables, 2004; 176453 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Willy Week, 2004; 176454 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Budget, 2005; 176455 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - College Coordinator, 2005; 176456 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Concessions, 2005; 176457 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Contacts, 2005; 176458 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Coordinator, 2005; 176459 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 2005; 176460 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Judges, 2005; 176461 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Meetings, 2005; 176462 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Parade, 2005; 176463 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Program, 2005; 176464 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Publicity, 2005; 176465 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Rules, 2005; 176466 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Security, 2005; 176467 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Sponsors, 2005; 176468 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Track, 2005; 176469 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Violations, 2005; 183671 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Area Coordinator, 2006; 176470 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Budget, 2006; 176471 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Campus-Wide Coordinator, 2006; 176472 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - College Coordinator, 2006; 176473 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Contacts, 2006; 176474 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 2006; 176475 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Judges Coordinator, 2006; 176476 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Media (CD), 2006; 176477 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      This CD contains Beer-Bike planning files. Excluding those that already existed in printed form, files were printed and placed within a corresponding subject folder.
    - Meetings, 2006; 176478 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Parade, 2006; 176479 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Program, 2006; 176480 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Publicity Coordinator, 2006; 176481 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Reports, 2006; 176485 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Results, 2006; 176482 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Rules, 2006; 176483 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Track, 2006; 176484 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Area Coordinator, 2007; 176486 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Budget, 2007; 176487 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Contacts, 2007; 176488 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 2007; 176489 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Guide to Beer Bike, 2007; 176490 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Media (CD), 2007; 176491 (Box 11, Folder 26)
      This CD contains Beer-Bike documents. There are a few files that cannot be opened, and it is unclear what program was used to create them. Excluding repeats, any files that could be opened were printed and placed within a corresponding subject folder.
    - Meetings, 2007; 176492 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Parade, 2007; 176493 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Reports, 2007; 176494 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Results, 2007; 176495 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Rules, 2007; 176496 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Schedule, 2007; 176497 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Track, 2007; 176498 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Unjackables, 2007; 176499 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Area Coordinator, 2008; 176500 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Budget, 2008; 176501 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Campus Wide Coordinator, 2008; 176502 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - College Coordinator, 2008; 176503 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Contacts, 2008; 176504 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 2008; 176505 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Judges, 2008; 176506 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Media (DVD), 2001-2008; 176507 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      This DVD mainly contains Beer-Bike documents from 2008, but there are also older files going back to 2001. There are a few files that cannot be opened, and it is unclear what program was used to create them. Excluding repeats, any files that could be opened were printed and placed within a corresponding subject folder.
    - Meetings, 2008; 176508 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Parade, 2008; 176509 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Reports, 2008; 176510 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Results, 2008; 176511 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Rules, 2008; 176512 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Schedule, 2008; 176513 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Track, 2008; 176514 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Violations, 2008; 183712 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Budget, 2009; 183713 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Communications packet, 2009; 183714 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 2009; 176516 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Fines, 2009; 183715 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Rules, 2009; 183716 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Schedule, 2009; 176517 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Track, 2009; 176518 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Subseries E: 2010-2019, 176245
    - Budget, 2010; 176519 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Communications packet, 2010; 183717 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Coordinators, 2010; 183718 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Judges, 2010; 176520 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Meetings, 2010; 183719 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Rules, 2010; 183720 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Schedules, 2010; 183721 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Willy Week, 2010; 183722 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Fines, 2011; 176521 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Rules, 2011; 183723 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Schedule, 2011; 183724 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Track, 2011; 183725 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Unjackables, 2011; 183726 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Fines, 2012; 183727 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Meetings, 2012; 183728 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Schedule, 2012; 183729 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Security, 2012; 183730 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Planning/Race, 2017-2018 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Planning/Race, 2019 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Subseries F: 2023
    - Judges, 2023 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Baker backpack, 2023 (Box 12)